Colin Stevens

Baltimore Web Developer

My Portfolio | GitHub Profile | LinkedIn Profile colinstevens06@gmail.com | 301-908-2196

Full-stack web developer with a passion for developing excellent work while providing outstanding customer service. Strong communicator who finds creative solutions to complex problems. Known by my clients for hitting deadlines and looking at the big picture. Known by my friends as loyal and artistic.

Technical Skills

- Advanced knowledge of ReactJS, Javascript (JQuery), MongoDB, ExpressJS, NodeJS, HTML5, CSS (Bootstrap and SASS), MySQL, ORMs, MVC Development, REST, CRUD, APIs, AJAX and Git
- Skilled with Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Moz Keyword Explorer
- Familiar with Photoshop, Lightroom CC, Illustrator, InDesign and Final Cut Pro

Projects

BMore Wings App

This is a full-stack MERN group project where I wrote the front- and back-end code. This was my concept: a hyper-local wings deals app, geared at providing users with the cheapest wings at local bars. Using ReactJS, I developed a reusable template for individual restaurant pages. I also put a focus on a smooth user experience, especially on mobile where I wrote a separate layout for the landing page. I also took the lead on back-end development, writing code for the basis of the program and the database, which populate's the pricing info.

- Technologies used: ReactJS, Express, MongoDB, NodeJS, JSX, SaSS, Heroku Deployed
- Links: <u>Deployed Project</u> and <u>GitHub Repo</u>

ReactJS Calculator

We started learning ReactJS so I wanted to dive in with a simple but useful application. I set out to create a calculator that looks like the one that comes standard with Macs. I created the buttons in the calculator dynamically, updated the state to allow my calculator logic to work.

- Technologies used: ReactJS, JSX, GitHub, CSS, HTML
- Links: <u>Deployed Project</u> and <u>GitHub Repo</u>

Lies From Granny Band Website

This was a side project to give me more practice on my design skills. I wanted to have a simple, art-focused design that we could use as a business toll. I wanted it to showcase the band to fans but also to venues looking for bands. There is a separate mobile design, including different hero images that are rendered (or not rendered) while on a mobile device. I also designed the graphics for the shows page using Illustrator.

- Technologies used: HTML, CSS (Bootstrap), Javascript
- Links: <u>Deployed Project</u> and <u>GitHub Repo</u>

Education

Johns Hopkins University

Certificate of Completion, 4/2020; Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Towson University

B.A. 12/2010; Majored in Journalism and minored in Business Administration

Professional Experience

Web Project Manager, University of Maryland Medical System, Baltimore, MD, 4/2018-Present

- Oversees major content overhauls to different sections of the website, focusing on service lines which target consumers searching for healthcare services in Baltimore
- Analyzes user traffic, using data to improve our site's user experience
- Researches keywords using various tools, like Moz Pro and Google Search Console, to determine the
 best strategies for search engine optimization. Because of this, we have seen continued increases in
 local traffic to our website
- Partners with physician leaders while developing new consumer-facing web projects

Web Project Coordinator, University of Maryland Medical System, Baltimore, MD, 6/2017-4/2018

- Contributed to the launch of a new system website, playing a key role in content migration and pre-launch content audits
- Managed day-to-day web projects for the University of Maryland Medical Center and System affiliates
- Ensured sites used best practices for Search Engine Optimization, using data to back decisions
- Coordinated implementation of new physician database consisting of more than 4,500 profiles

Communications Specialist, University of Maryland Medical System, Baltimore, MD, 2/2016-6/2017

- Wrote and edited stories for various publications, including quarterly and monthly newsletters
- Managed and executed web projects from conception to completion for two high-priority service lines
- Audited web content, implementing improvements to IA and UX via our CMS
- Maintained physician profiles in the mobile app and online databases

Media Relations Specialist, MD-National Capital Park & Planning Commission, Riverdale, MD, 2/2015-1/2016

- Wrote and distributed news releases
- Pitched stories to media outlets to promote department programs, services and facilities
- Shot, edited, wrote scripts and voiced video packages on departmental programs

Service Manager, Chipotle Mexican Grill, Germantown, MD, 10/2013-6/2014

- Supervised a staff of 30 while managing day-to-day operations
- Oversaw hiring and training of new employees

Sports Reporter, The Gazette, Laurel, MD, 10/2012-7/2013

- Covered the beats for volleyball, ice hockey, boys lacrosse and football
- Developed and pitched multiple stories on a weekly basis
- Used social media frequently to promote stories and break news

Multimedia Sports Reporter, Public Opinion Newspaper, Chambersburg, PA, 8/2011-10/12

- Reported daily on 12 high schools and three colleges on multiple media platforms
- Produced weekly video packages including game coverage, features and talk shows
- Managed multiple social media accounts to promote stories and break news
- Chosen as an award-winning writer for the 2012 Professional Keystone Press Awards, Division IV